Kris Flemington

07980 690 896 kris.flemington@gmail.com

49 Armadale Road Woking, Surrey, GU 21 3LB

SKILLS

- Marketing Strategy
- Brand Strategy
- Comms Planning
- Advertising Strategy
- Customer Experience
- Channel Strategy
- Research
- Measurement & ROI
- Marketing Effectiveness
- Marketing analytics
- Workshops & facilitation

PROFILE

A marketing strategist & consultant who specialises in building brands and driving commercial impact. With 20yrs experience working with some iconic brands, I have a proven track record in marketing strategy and execution which delivers commercial impact. I partner marketing teams, helping them wrestle their problems, researching, setting and measuring marketing, brand, CX and comms strategy. I believe in partnering with clients on much more than just communications – it only works when it *all* works.

EXPERIENCE

Global Strategy Partner, Ogilvy — July 2019 to Present

Nestlé Waters: Responsible for world-wide brand and creative strategy across the San Pellegrino product portfolio.

 I unified disconnected cross market brand and communication strategies slashing duplicated marketing budgets and delivering budget savings of just over 32%.

British Airways & IAG group: I led strategy for Team Horizon – functioning as an independent agency drawn from 5 WPP companies, we delivered the full range of marketing, creative and consultancy services from brand to loyalty, digital and full media planning and buying.

• During both strikes and the pandemic, I partnered the CMO through the toughest commercial period in living memory to deliver a brand and communications strategy which ensured we outsold the competition 4.5:1 as the world opened up, safeguarding BA's survival.

BA Amex & IAG Loyalty: Consulting to the COO & CMO of IAG loyalty on the future of loyalty for the IAG group, their direct-to-consumer strategy and finance brands.

- I led the relaunch of the BA Amex card which achieved +22% growth year on year for the business in a stagnant market.
- I led the development and launch of the new BA Mastercard; from product development, through to positioning, identity and the launch campaign, beating penetration targets by 6%.

Group Strategy Director, Crispin Porter & Bogusky — May 2017 to July 2019 I led the strategy across CPB's global accounts, Expedia/Hotels.com, PayPal, American Airlines and Betstars. I was also responsible for the training and development of the London Strategy team.

• For Hotels.com, in a competitive UK market my strategy achieved an 18% increase in penetration.

Strategy Director, Freelance — September 2016 to May 2017

As an independent marketing strategist, I worked directly with both brands, agencies and other consultancies. These included Aston Martin, FutureLab, PRISM, Leo Burnett and Crispin Porter & Bogusky.

Head of Strategy (London) & Head of Data & Analytics (Europe) JWT London, — April 2013 to September 2016

At JWT I had 3 parts to my role. As Head of Strategy I line managed and directed a team of 13 strategists. I built an in-house data and analytics capability to service JWTs European offices and client base. I led strategy on Mazda Europe, Aston Martin and Canon Europe.

- From a standing start our small analytics team generated £1.15m in incremental revenue in just over 12months.
- For Mazda, I developed a brand experience strategy which uplifted sales by 14% year on year.

Head of Response Planning & Strategy Director, VCCP London, — March 2010 to April 2013

A fully integrated, but content and digital heavy account, I led commercial, brand, and comms strategy across O2 and Telefonica Europe. I set up and directed a marketing effectiveness programme to ensure ROMI and line managed a team of 5 Strategists and Data Planners.

- Successfully developed a new brand & creative strategy which halted a 9% decline in value share turning it into +3.1% year on year increase in an extremely competitive market.
- The same campaign won Campaign Magazine's campaign of the year and a D&AD Pencil.

OTHER ROLES

Senior Strategist, OgilvyOne London, — August 2006 to March 2010

A Strategy on British Telecom, Zurich Insurance, IBM and eHarmony.

Strategist Tidalwave London, — September 2002 to March 2010

B2B digital strategy across Hewlett Packard, Microsoft, Vodafone, Blackberry & Kingston technology.

EDUCATION

BA (hons) Marketing & Consumer behaviour, with economics and corporate strategy. University of Plymouth Business School.

WPP Maestro - Leadership training programme